# Raúl Calderón

# Web Developer

#### Raúl Francisco Calderón Rochín

Hermosillo Sonora, MX.

+52 644 143 9913
raul41092@gmail.com
Online Resume



## **About me**

I'm a developer with almost 10 years of experience. I've been working remotely for many clients from Mexico and the United States. I know how to team work and I enjoy learning new technologies and new skills from the people around me.

Skills

HTML PHP

CSS PYTHON

BOOTSTRAP WORDPRESS/CMS

JAVASCRIPT DRUPAL
AJAX MYSQL
JQUERY GIT

Work history

## Powdevs - BillingTree | A REPAY Company / Web Developer

2020 - 2024

- Bring support and new functionalities to a payment system used in many hospitals in the USA called "Ipayx".
- Address and fix problems or bugs caused on a production environment using control versions.
- Generate XML or PDF reports with the information of the daily, monthly or annually payments.
- Created a two factor autenticator (2FA) for application logins and sessions.

# **Rivka Development - Sales Simplicity Software, Inc. /** Web Developer

2019 - 2020

- Bring support and new functionalities to a WordPress
  customized plugin known as "Options Online", which is used for
  many clieints in the USA and allows dynamically to show the
  information of a website used to sell residential houses in the
  United States: Sales Simplicity.
- Export XML files with the sales and houses info as reports.

#### Vagapp Soluciones / Web Developer

2015 - 2019

- At charge of developing many projects for multiple clients, most of them in Mexico. Some of those projects were:
- WedProduction: A totally customized web page that was created in Drupal, which is used as a wedding social media, where you are allowed to quote, look for professionals, create events, etc.
- VisitMexico: A website that is used to see all the upcoming events in Mexico state.
- Arizona Driver Club (AZ Drivers): A web page that was given support in some functionalities, such as quote insurance for cars.

#### **Education**

**Instituto Tecnológico de Sonora (ITSON) /** Software Engineer 2011 - 2015

The career was completed in that period of time.

# Languages

- Spanish (native)
- English (advanced)

\_\_\_

# **Courses and Certificates**

# Certificated in "Creación de páginas web responsive con Bootstrap".

The course was taken on Udemy.

## GIT CERTIFICATION..

The course was taken on Desafios Latam.

## INTRODUCTION TO DATA ANALYSIS WITH PYTHON.

The course was taken on Udemy.

# PYTHON FOR DATA SCIENCE - Machine Learning with Python.

The course was taken on Desafios Latam.

## AI & ChatGPT From Zero to Advanced.

The course was taken on Udemy.